IL Cafe we have you
covered welcome to Il Cafe we're about
to discuss motor insurance today and you
know the thing is I've realized that you
think the question and we bring you the
answer even before you can say the
questions out in in words and that's how
quick we are I'm uh in a very self-
congratulatory mode as you can see today
but uh you get the drift over here we've
got a few of your questions answered on
today's show that is all about the Dig
motor claim Journey so we've got an
expert who's going to be joining us from
the IC Lombard family today he's a he's
a leader with several years of
experience Rajiv mirani is joining us
he's vice president customer service
motor and strategy uh thank you s thank
you for having me here and would like to
give insight about the mclims journey on
the digital site which is a new age uh a
landscape of technology using technology
and uh making customer life easier and I
thought you know we should start with an
icebreaker question because just this
morning I was thinking about the very
first car that I ever owned with my own
money and that was a I think esteem one
of those old you know maroon color
esteem is what I had but I'm sure you
know each one of us has a special memory
associated with vehicles that we have
owned what's yours Raji before we get
into the business end of the
conversation all right so same here you
know that time or those days uh we were
having all maruti so I even started my
journey with uh 800 Mar 800 which used
to be a public car or the famous car and
uh I still remember that was one of the
best Trails on those days and uh we
learned you know how to drive on this
particular car it was a you know family
car for those days you know you are
lucky Rajiv if you learned on one I
learned in a Fiat so for us you know any
Mari 00 of the road was like wow what a
what a car so I completely hear you nice
family car a nice way to you know sort
of remember those days on a show like
this one as well and then of move into
the business end of questions we've
heard so much you know uh with respect
to the sector evolving and with respect
specifically to motor claims and would
be good to understand what has changed
with respect to customer expectations
and the industry landscape uh in the
last say few years or so according to
you Rajiv so on the motor claim side
basically you know the objective of the
insurance uh companies is to make
customers life easier by you know using
technology and uh when we say technology
uh there are a lot of initiatives being
a industry leader we have taken a lot of
initiatives and you know we have
launched uh certain industry first
initiatives like uh you know Cloud
calling eclaims paperless Journey instas
SP then we have uh cashless garages
Network and uh you know so many so we we
keep on you know adding uh features for
you know making the life easier and you
know provide a better experience to the
customers you mentioned quite a few of
these interventions Rajiv would be good
for our customers our viewers to
understand what each of these is really
all about and what paino or challenge or
need gap does it address so if you could
take one by one and explain a little bit
more to us so s basically for customer
it's a pain you know is already going
through a pain of you know accident
which is unfortunate event for him and
we would not like our customer to face
that but in case the need arises we are
there to support uh from starting from
ination to uh the payment Journey so end
to end Journey we want to support the
customer we want to stand with the
customers uh and ensure that you know he
doesn't face any challenges so if we
talk about the initiatives uh you know
uh recently we have launched uh Cloud
calling features so basically this
featur is is all about you know we are
empowering customers to connect with our
claims manager uh through one single
point uh contact number and the customer
can you know get the query addressed
from Real Time b as in when required
okay so that uh all the customer queries
are not remain unanswered that is the
objective and secondly the benefit is
all these calls are recorded uh so you
know we get uh we get a chance to
analyze those calls and train the team
on the you know soft skill as well as uh
the query resolutions okay so we keep on
you know uh improving our skill sets and
our Communications that's the objective
so this uh you know till date if we talk
about we were able to you know solve the
queries of customers uh almost 95% plus
and we were able to connect uh more than
10 lakh customers as on today right and
uh see generally what happens is in
traditional ways uh nobody you know
wants to Face customer or nobody uh you
know people uh uh skips to connect to
customer and give a better experience or
you know comfort you know sitting at
their homes so customer need not to
visit garages because and they feel that
you know they are not aware of the
process so customer if you guide
properly they will be you know taken
care and there'll be a smooth journey
and the seamless experience what we are
looking at so that's all about
Cloud calling if we talk about there's a
inst aspect where you know customer can
connect with us on Real Time Business uh
sitting at their home through online uh
application where we are able to you
know get vehicle surveyed with an
approval right on the you know call so
that customer need not to worry about
you know when the survey will happen how
survey will happen and you know how long
it will take to provide an approval
because traditionally it was taking a
lot of time
so involvement of garages Etc which is
not the case here we we are there to you
know attend the customer calls and the
you know survey on real time bis so how
that is what we are solving through
instas speec then we have eclaim uh so
earlier you know traditionally all the
industry you know takes lot of paperwork
so customer feeli you know submitting a
lot of papers uh and you know signing
papers Etc so here we are saying you
just need not to submit any paper
physical papers so we provide online
Link where customer can fill the you
know minimum bare minimum details and uh
that's it you can also upload the
document online so need not to visit any
garage need not to visit any offices we
do not call customer at our branches so
that uh you know it's easy for customer
to file a claim right it's not uh
difficult for him to make a claim uh and
eclaim is also available with ckyc
online right so otherwise noway Cy kyc
is another you know you have to submit
extra paper for address proof ID proof
Etc which is not the case here so we do
this with eclaim only and then we have
Breakin application which is you know AI
enabled which helps customer to renew
the policy uh setting at their homes on
the real timeis So within you know 78
minutes the uh you know approvals are
given so you can issue the policy uh on
immediate basis there is no need to wait
no need to you know wait for surveyor to
inspect the vehicle at home next day and
third day and you know takes time so
that's all about uh breaking app
WhatsApp Journey so now customers are
very happy to you know have the updates
on realtime studies because there are
lot of stages in the claims like you
know intimation surveyor is appointed
surveyor inspects the vehicle and then
you know approvals are given then the
repairs uh starts and the repair
completion then delivery order and you
know the liability one so everything is
on Real Time basis on daily basis we
keep on updating our status on the
customer mobile so that he's able to you
know view the real time status of claim
so that he need not to call anyone he
need not to you know worry about what is
happening on my car we are even showing
them you know real status also so he can
have a complete view about the claim
status on daily so that's the objective
and then we have you know chat boards
voice boards where customer can even you
know raise the query or the you know
address their queries even if he don't
want to talk that is also physic so s
basically you know uh to make the life
easy and you know seamless to provide
better experience to customers we have
you know initiatives we have already
taken this initiatives like uh instas
spect Cloud calling WhatsApp Journey
then eclaim paperless uh you know
Journeys and uh inbu ckyc Breakin
application so we have done lot of uh
usage of Technology uh to make uh you
know process simple and uh easy there's
one more phrase right you know that sort
of captured my imagination because we've
heard cashless in the context of Health
Right medical claims cashless
hospitalization but a cashless garage is
a new new phrase that I'm hearing I'm
thinking uh what amazing use cases there
could be for something like this we all
recently you know a few months ago we
read about uh the floods in chenai and
we used to wonder at that time you
always think about the pain that the
person is going through having lost all
these luxury cars just because of rain
Mother Nature um tell us a little bit in
the context of uh you know how this
helps consumers so thank you SE for
bringing you know uh this castless
discussion so castless is a facility for
you know customer uh to Avail that
benefit so that customer needed to Bear
the entire cost of caim and you know pay
from pocket and then go through the you
know reimbursement process which is
ideally a leny to avoid that you know
inconvenience to our customers what we
have made is we have uh you know set up
the arrangement of the garage across all
locations across all em manufacturers so
that as and when the claim arises we
arrange the cess facility at that
particular garage and we ensure that
customer just pay the you know minimum
amount what he's supposed to pay and uh
rest entire you know the bill or the
liability is paid to garage directly
without any hurdles and customer need
not to wait for you know reimbursement
of claim uh which generally takes you
know 15 to 20 days time and we cut down
this process in short uh Gess is a big
benefit for the PO holders and uh we
would like to you know extend all all
the support to our customers to you know
arrange this facility uh and use this
facility to make their life uh
comfortable and uh hree on the next
Point C uh Cyclone Mong uh which
happened recently in Chennai uh that you
know lot of customers uh Vehicles got
affected even the you know and we we
understood the you know impact of this
uh particular tragedy uh and what we did
is uh we arranged Manpower from
different locations and you know uh we
arrang a task force in Chennai to uh you
know first to address the or to you know
provide empathy to customers by you know
standing with them and supporting them
by you know arranging Towing Vans and
even the you know appointment to the
garages uh we did certain you know camps
in the society so that customers are you
know uh given some relief in terms of
you know they we are there with them to
support the claims or you know whatever
help we we were able to extend so we we
expanded the teams we sent the experts
across the officials and uh we started
you know arranging uh pickups and uh
appointment Etc with the garage and then
we started assessing the law and today
uh I'm very happy that you know within a
month's time we were able to deliver or
you know settle off 80 more than 80% of
claims within a short notice where you
know people were uh if you look at the
industry this numbers would not be that
big but yes we were focused we we are
having enough teams uh to coate with the
customers we were able to deliver these
numbers uh in a very short span of time
right and the customer were happy we get
lot of appreciation from customers
saying you know we were lucky to have
insurance with you is the reason we are
today you know out of this uh trauma
that's a very powerful story about how
you know not just technology but teams
can come together to address you know
people's concerns at a time when
everything seems to be up in the air you
don't know where to go what to do you're
Frozen because this is not something
that you anticipate and it happens to
you so um that that's a lovely lovely
story that you shared with us with
respect to the power of putting together
processes that make a customer's life so
easy even in challenging times like uh
the example that you gave us in summary
you know Rajiv is there anything that
you would like to leave our viewers with
when they think about motor claim
process any last words from uh you as
someone who heads that particular area
for us so uh so basically see of course
digital uh process digital
digitalization of claims process is uh
uh equally important but you know we
also know that you know physical touch
is equally important so we always you
know touch B the customer once in a uh
you know the claim process so that we do
not miss uh you know the opportunity to
get feedback from the customers and uh
we also wanted to understand the pulse
of the you know customers so that we are
constantly you know building up the
process building up the uh technology
and uh you know deliver the promises
what we have made while you know
purchasing the policy and by you know
doing all this efforts are basically to
ensure that we are transparent we are
fair we are you know responsible and we
we you know care for customer is the you
know uh theme or the objective of this
uh claim process right or to make you
know life easier during the entire
Journey end to end Journey we want to be
there with the customers and we assure
that you know our customers uh in
whatever situation there are we are
there for them and we will always be uh
you know willing to extend our best
possible efforts and support during the
challenging times before I wrap up the
conversation remember right in the
beginning we spoke about the first ever
car and we uh refreshed some of our old
memories I thought you know maybe some
more memories to sign off the
conversation because a car is integral
it's a part of our life right it takes
us to places it's it's more it's
symbolic of Continuum in in many ways
and music is part of that Journey so I I
was wondering you know do you also have
like a playlist because when I get into
the car I have a particular playlist
that I like to listen to it's got a mix
it's got some old kishor Kumar songs it
has some arit Singh songs it has some
English old 80s music as well what's
your go-to song or set of songs when you
are
driving I'm fan of you know SP balas
'90s you know there there were a lot of
famous songs he song for us and the
voice
of that is memorable I think you and I
have something in common over here
because one of my favorite set of songs
to listen to are from many I don't know
why but on long drives I really like to
listen all of the
songs but and ashiki that's not STV but
ashiki songs are out of the world uh so
the yeah right you agree right
sjan correct
right great music in the 90s anyway
that's our drive time playlist I hope
our listeners have taken away some
things to add to their own playlists as
they drive out and please do remember to
dri safe and belt up not just in the
front seats but also in the back seats
if you have kids make sure they're
always belted up and on that note uh let
us wrap up the show thank you so much
Raji for joining us on I Cafe today
thank you s for having us here thank you
so much